

# Resume

# **Eskinder Getahun**

E-Mail : eskinderget@gmail.com
www : <a href="https://eskinderg.github.io">https://eskinderg.github.io</a>

Mobile: +251-911-184987

As confirmed by my portfolio content and code, I combine my knowledge, experience and skills with technology in order to develop professional and innovative web applications.

By following the best practices, I produce a clean code that is comprehensive and easy to maintain.

- Full Stack Developer in the design and development of web application, implementation of Object-Oriented Design(OOD) in Angular and C#.
- Proficiency in developing front-end, Single Page Application (SPA) using Angular, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Typescript.
- Proficient in Angular, Angular Material and worked as MEAN Stack developer.
- Proficient in developing web applications using Node.js, Express.js and MVC technologies.
- Experience in Web API, MVC, N-Tier Architecture, Relational Database Design, and Non-Relational Database Design.
- In-depth knowledge & experience of software Design Patterns including Singleton, Prototype, Factory, and Unit of Work, Repository Pattern.
- Experience in Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) and Object-Data Modeling (ODM) using ADO.NET, EntityFramework, LINQ and Lambda expression.
- Experience in design and implementation of Relational Database including Normalization, Stored Procedures, Triggers, Views and User Defined Functions in MS SQL Server.
- Proficient in writing test cases and using unit tests including NUnit and Jasmine to validate development releases with in Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodology.
- Proficient in Agile, JIRA and Waterfall SDLC methodologies.
- Proficient in Version Control tools such as Git.

#### **Education**

Bachelor's (B.Sc) in Computer Science & Information Technology from the *University of Arba-Minch, Ethiopia* (04/2004 - 11/2008).

## **Technical Skills**

- Front End Languages: Angular, JQuery, SAAS, NodeJS, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript.
- Back End Languages: C#, ASP.NET MVC, NETCORE.
- Testing Frameworks: Mocha, Jasmine, Sinon.
- Database Systems: MySQL, MSSQL.
- Code Quality: Code Climate
- Application IDE: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, VIM, Neovim.
- Versioning Tool: Git.
- Webservers: Apache, http-server, IIS, ExpressJS.
- **SEO:** Google Analytics.
- Full Understanding of OOP.
- ASP.Net MVC 5 using Entity Framework and modern architectural patterns.
- RESTful API programming.

+251-911-184987

# **Professional Experience**

### **Freelance Full Stack Developer (Present)**

#### Full Stack Web Developer

- Created SPA, user interactive (UI) web pages using web technologies like HTML5, SASS, Typescript, Angular2 and Bootstrap.
- Created and used Reducers that received Actions to modify the store State.
- Created Action dispatch to deploy Actions to add Dynamic Functionality
- Created custom NPM modules.
- Developed administrative UI Components using Angular2, Typescript and Webpack
- Used Bootstrap for Responsive Web design.
- Optimized Front-end assets for speed and performance
- Used Middleware, Redux-Promise in application to retrieve data from Back-End and to perform RESTFUL services.
- Created custom Angular Components including Breadcrumbs, Reactive Forms, Form Validators, Tabbed Components and Toggle Buttons.

## Nuaxis (09/2016 - 07/2017)

# Front End Developer

- Created programs as per user / design requirements using AngularJS.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams (DEV, UX/UI & BA) to define, design, and deliver creative digital solutions.
- Utilized, automated unit tests and integration tests for application life cycle.
- Executed Agile Development techniques.
- Utilized industry best practices to create effective business solutions for clients.
- Participated and contributed towards senior-level technology discussions.
- Created web forms using bootstrap.
- Used Git flow techniques for feature branching, merging and continuous integration.
- Implemented Google Analytics using Angularitics.
- Participated on OAuth implementation for user's role and permissions using JWT (JSON web token).
- Created migration scripts for Postgres database systems using Sequelize ORM.
- Consumed back-end web API.
- Produced reports and statistical information for managers using code climate, mocha and other testing framework.
- Used bootstrap CSS to create, modify and update web layouts.
- Created angular 1.5 components and directives for front-end validation and routing.
- Used Node JS schema validator for backend validation.
- Performed unit and integration test for front-end and back-end systems using AngularJS and NodeJS.

# Bloomberg BNA (11/2015 - 07/2016)

#### Software Engineer II

- E-Commerce development using Agile methodologies.
- Full Stack web development using ASP .Net MVC, C#, Angularjs and MS-SQL.
- Provided support for intranet applications for strategic migration.
- Integrated ASP.NET MVC application with Ektron system.
- Designed modern architectural patterns for intranet systems.
- Wrote Front-end and Back-end Unit Tests for code re-factoring.
- Provided statistical information for senior managers.

# Freelance (02/2015 - 11/2015)

#### Freelance Web Developer

- Full Stack development using LAMP stack.
- Customized, Implemented custom WordPress themes and plugins.
- Maintained website for most up-to date technology, software, and information
- Developed and implemented mobile device responsive UI designs and back-end analytic tracking.

# Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia. (09/2013 - 01/2015)

#### Web Developer

- Designed visual layout of websites.
- Provided IT support for various user groups.
- Created Stored Procedures using MSSQL.
- Tested a website before it goes live and identify problems.
- Advised users on the functionality of the website.
- Changed code of an existing website using MVC, C#, Entity Framework and LINQ technologies.
- Optimized web assets for optimal speed and performance.
- Produced reports and statistical information for senior managers using various reporting tools.

# HST Consulting, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (07/2012 - 08/2013)

#### System Administrator

- Maintained configuration of network equipment's and web services.
- Managed Active Directory Users and Computers.
- Provided support for various User.
- Produced reports and statistical information for senior managers.
- Managed network protocols, file sharing services, file backups and intranet web services.

# **Trainings**

Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP).

Microsoft Certified C# Programming Specialist.

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Certificate.

**Managing Microsoft Active Directory & Users.**